Javad Adib







Full Stack PHP Developer, Software Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. A microservice architecture lover because of the freedom of technology and scalability. Collaboration with dozens of specialists and teamwork led to the acquisition of valuable knowledge. Built infrastructures of 7+ multi-million \$ projects from scratch. The learner who knows how to learn. A deep understanding of eCommerce. Open-source enthusiast.

mr.javad.adib@gmail.com



+98-935-726-9759



Professional Experience

Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

Jibres Iran

(2 years 5 months) 12/2019 - present

- Implemented an integrated cloud eCommerce solution for 1,000+ businesses containing website, app, PoS software, CRM, CMS, accounting software, ticketing system, and form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced the new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated the native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

Founder, CEO, and Software Engineer

Ermile Iran

(4 years 7 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from an Angel investor, spearheaded the 15 members' cross-functional team, and launched a product that earned about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

Computer Lecturer

Teacher Iran

(13 years 7 months) 06/2006 - 04/2019

- Taught 2,000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, and private classes.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to an acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers from around the world.

Web UI/UX Designer

Freelancer Iran (6 years 10 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed and developed 40+ WordPress websites with HTML5 and CSS3, user experience, and communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, and celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

Volunteer work

DevOps and Frontend Developer

Khadije Charity Iran (4 years 4 months) 12/2017 - 03/2022

Developed the website and all the software infrastructure to accelerate and fulfilled the wishes of 110,000+ people.

Software Solutions for Business - Expert

WorldSkills Iran Iran (5 years 4 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

Tutored and trained three talents who have won silver and two bronze medals in national competitions; held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

Education

M.S. in IT Management

Azad University Tehran, Iran 2015 - 2022

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Azad University Nour, Iran

2008 - 2014

Skills

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Python, Bash Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML Web Service SOAP, REST API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony

Front-end JS Library ¡Query, Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, Angular

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Version Control System Git, Github, Gitlab

Test Driven Development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework UI cPanel, DirectAdmin Network DNS, DHCP, HTTP, SSL, TLS, SMTP, FTP, MIME, SSH OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi Software Development Methodology Scrum, Agile, Kanban Microsoft Office Specialist Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma Miscellaneous Cloud Development, SaaS, Database Design, Algorithm, QA, Object Orientated, A/B Testing, OWASP, CORS, XML, XHTML, Twig, AJAX, PWA, SCSS, NPM, Composer, CLI, LEMP, LAMP, Wireguard, Accounting, Maintenance, VoIP, AWS

Awards and Honors

Membership Iran National Elites Foundation 2013

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business Medallion for Excellence

Mashhad, Iran 2008

Yazd, Iran

2009

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

Languages English Fluent C1

Silver Medal

Persian Native